<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<eventlog>
<event added="2002-07-30 00:00" start="2002-07-30 00:00" 
end="2002-07-30 00:00" author="SJP" number="9">A routine test of the MST Radar relays was conducted.</event>
<event added="2002-08-27 00:00" start="2002-08-27 00:00" 
end="2002-08-27 00:00" author="SJP" number="10">The hard-drive on the Master-PC, which controls the MST Radar, failed on 27th August. It was replaced almost immediately by the nominally identical Backup-PC
 and normal operations were resumed with only a minor loss of coverage. The working hard-drive on the Backup-PC has been cloned so that the PC can be repaired quickly in the event of another hard-drive failure. Tests have shown 
that the Backup-PC works with the cloned hard-drive. Although the Master and Backup PCs were supposed to be identical, there are slight differences between
them which means that the Master-PC does not function correctly with the cloned hard-drive.
Efforts to restore the Master-PC to working order are on-going. It is thought that the interface
and network drivers will need to be reinstalled.</event>
<event added="2002-10-01 00:00" start="2002-10-01 00:00" 
end="2002-10-02 00:00" author="ZKO" number="12">
Communications with the radar site were briefly interrupted on 1st October when a hedge trimmer
accidentally cut through telephone lines approximately 1 km away. Although telephone
and computer connections were restored later the same day, the Met Office's ISDN line remained
inoperative for approximately 24 hours.</event>
<event added="2002-10-31 00:00" start="2002-10-31 00:00" 
end="2002-10-31 00:00" author="ZKO" number="13">
On 31st October maintenance work was carried out on the site PC, which logs surface data, in
order to replace a failed fan unit.</event>
<event added="2002-11-04 00:00" start="2002-11-04 00:00" 
end="2002-11-04 00:00" author="ZKO" number="14">A routine test and replacement of faulty relays.</event>
<event added="2002-11-15 00:00" start="2002-11-15 00:01" 
end="2002-12-11 00:00" author="ZKO" number="15">The Met Office is currently phasing-in a new data acquisition system. During late November
it was necessary to make changes to the programs which write the MST Radar data to BUFR
files so that the header and footer codes were acceptable by the new system.</event>
<event added="2002-11-18 00:00" start="2002-11-18 00:00" 
end="2002-11-18 00:00" author="ZKO" number="16">
The new UFAM mobile lidar system arrived at the MST Radar site on 18th November, approximately
a month later than originally expected. The instrument will be operated at the site
in-between field campaigns.</event>
<event added="2002-12-11 00:00" start="2002-12-11 00:00" 
end="2002-12-11 00:00" author="ZKO" number="17">
A successful switch-over of BUFR file transmission to the new system was carried out on 11th December.</event>
<event added="2002-12-17 00:00" start="2002-12-17 00:00" 
end="2002-12-17 00:00" author="ZKO" number="18">
The local electricity supplier shut down power to the Capel Dewi area on 17th December so
that they could carry out scheduled maintenance work on their systems. The radar remained
out of action for 7 hours. </event>
<event added="2002-12-28 00:00" start="2002-12-28 00:00" 
end="2002-12-28 00:00" author="ZKO" number="19">
A brief power failure in the early morning of Saturday 28th December
caused the radar system to crash. The problem was not noticed until the following day when
Dave Wareing rebooted the radar control computer; ZAKO was on holiday at the time.</event>
<event added="2003-01-12 00:00" start="2003-01-12 16:30" 
end="2003-01-13 09:30" author="ZKO" number="20">
The transmitter to which the others are phase-locked developed a fault around 1630 GMT on
12th January 2003, a Sunday. The problem wasn't noticed until first thing the following morning
when the faulty transmitter was repaired, around 0930 GMT. The data for this period are
unreliable.</event>
<event added="2003-01-13 00:00" start="2003-01-13 00:00" 
end="2003-01-13 00:00" author="ZKO" number="21">
The radar remained out of action for approximately another 2 hours on the morning of 13th
January to allow students from the Geography Department, University of Wales Aberystwyth,
to measure the orientation of the MST Radar antenna array. This is the 3rd time that students
have practised their surveying skills on the antenna array.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:23" start="2003-04-01 00:00" 
end="2003-10-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="27">The most significant problems experienced during the last six months have been caused by
computer worms (MS-Blaster and subsequently Nachi-A) infecting theWindows2000 PC which
controls the climate data logger; the Met Office had similar problems with their PC which collects
GPS water vapour receiver data at the radar site. It should be noted that the data logger PC
was running up to date anti-virus software, which was initially unable to remove the worms.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:19" start="2003-04-03 00:00" 
end="2003-04-14 00:00" author="ZKO" number="26">A problem with the wind measuring equipment at Frongoch farm lead to a loss of surface wind
data between 3rd and 14th April. At first it was thought that the anemometer had developed a
fault and that it would need to be sent back to Campbell Scientific for repairs. A hand winch
was purchased to enable the tower to be lowered to ground level for inspection. ZAKO traced
the source of the problem to corrosion of an electrical connector between the wind measuring
equipment and the data logging unit. He cleaned and then thoroughly resealed the connector in
order to avoid a repetition of the problem.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:35" start="2003-06-16 00:00" 
end="2003-06-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="29">The JANET connection to the radar site suffered a temporary disruption on 16th June. The
problem was found to be caused by a tree rubbing against the telephone cables approximately
1 km away. The JANET connection was restored later the same day.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:08" start="2003-07-09 00:00" 
end="2003-07-09 00:00" author="ZKO" number="22">The programme of reconditioning the transmitter cooling blower motors has enabled the transmitters
to be run at higher power than has been possible for some time. An increase of approximately
20% was introduced on 9th July and there are plans to gradually step this up in the near
future.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:10" start="2003-07-19 06:00" 
end="2003-07-21 09:00" author="ZKO" number="23">A problem developed on the radar receiver interface board at approximately 0600 UT on 19th
July, i.e. on a Saturday morning. Consequently it was not noticed, and rectied, until the
Monday morning leading to a loss of approximately 48 hours worth of data. The problem was
thought to be caused by a static build-up associated with a thunder storm. There was a series of
brief electricity supply interruptions around the same time which caused damage to pin diodes
in 3 transmitters.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:34" start="2003-07-25 00:00" 
end="2003-07-25 00:00" author="ZKO" number="28">ZAKO cleaned the tipping bucket raingauge on 25th July in order to remove a build-up of fungus
which was obstructing the flow of rainwater through a narrow tube. The in-line filters are
regularly cleaned as recommended by Campbell Scientific.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:17" start="2003-07-26 00:00" 
end="2003-07-28 09:00" author="ZKO" number="24">a short circuit on one of the relay cables
caused the radar beam steering unit to lock in one direction. The fact that this problem also developed
on a Saturday morning meant that it was again almost 48 hours before it was rectified.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:17" start="2003-08-27 00:00" 
end="2003-08-27 00:00" author="ZKO" number="25">The radar was down for approximately 10 minutes on 27th August after a minor disruption of
the mains electricity supply to the site.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:52" start="2003-10-20 00:00" 
end="2003-10-20 00:00" author="ZKO" number="38">Dr Prabhakaran Nayar, from the University of Kerala, India visited the radar site on 20th October 2003.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:46" start="2003-10-21 10:30" 
end="2003-10-21 12:40" author="ZKO" number="32">A relay control unit, located within the antenna array, failed at around 1030 UT on 21st October 2003.
The problem was fixed by 1240 UT on the same day.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:38" start="2003-10-30 00:00" 
end="2003-10-30 00:00" author="ZKO" number="30">On 30th October 2003 changes were made to the standard mode observation specification. The main
objective was to remove a 10 minute break in observations, which occurred approximately every 10
hours when the radar control software switched from one schedule to the next. The schedule length
was also increased to approximately 27 hours in order to simplify the specification for continuous operations.
The existing radar control and acquisition software is still optimised for making fixed duration
observations and there are plans to upgrade it in the near future.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:49" start="2003-11-06 00:00" 
end="2003-11-06 00:00" author="ZKO" number="36">MSc students from the Institute of Geography and Earth Sciences, UWA, visited the site on 6th November
2003. They measured the orientation of the MST radar antenna array as part of a surveying practical.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:47" start="2003-11-06 00:00" 
end="2003-11-06 00:00" author="ZKO" number="33">The side panels of the power distribution box,
which is also located within the antenna array, were replaced on 6th November 2003. The old panels
had become rotten.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:48" start="2003-11-06 00:00" 
end="2003-11-06 00:00" author="ZKO" number="34">NERC Site survey.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:40" start="2003-11-07 13:00" 
end="2003-11-11 13:00" author="ZKO" number="31">The MST radar was operated in a user-specified mode for 
approximately 72 hours starting at 1300 UT
on 7th November 2003. The main objective was to collect IQ data, which are not normally recorded.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:52" start="2003-11-19 00:00" 
end="2003-12-02 00:00" author="ZKO" number="37">Between 19th November and 2nd December 2003, the UFAM (Universities Facility for Atmospheric
Measurement) boundary-layer wind-profiler was away from the radar site. It was taken to Southampton
to test whether it was likely to suffer interference from the proposed Galileo global positioning system. The latter will operate in the same frequency band as many wind-profilers.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:48" start="2003-11-20 00:00" 
end="2003-11-20 00:00" author="ZKO" number="35">NERC asbestos check.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:54" start="2003-11-26 00:00" 
end="2003-11-28 00:00" author="ZKO" number="40">Site manager away visiting the MO's new VHF wind-profiler at South Uist (Outer Hebrides) from
26th to 28th November 2003.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:53" start="2003-12-12 00:00" 
end="2003-12-12 00:00" author="ZKO" number="39">Dr Adrian McDonald, from the University of Canterbury, New Zealand, visited the site on 12th December 2003.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:56" start="2004-01-28 00:00" 
end="2004-01-28 00:00" author="ZKO" number="41">Members of the Health and Safety Committee of the RAL Space Science and Technology Department
visited the radar site on 28th January 2004. They found no significant problems and made only minor
recommendations for improvements. </event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:59" start="2004-02-05 00:00" 
end="2004-02-09 00:00" author="ZKO" number="44">The MO's ISDN line to the radar site developed an intermittent fault on 5th February 2004. ZAKO
identified and reported the problem to BT on the same day. Nevertheless the problem became persistent
and the line was not restored to full working order until the 9th. </event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:01" start="2004-02-15 00:00" 
end="2004-02-15 00:00" author="ZKO" number="45">The MO's ISDN line to the radar site developed an intermittent fault similar to the one reported on the 5th February 2004. recurred on 15th (once
again ZAKO reported it to BT on the same day) and was fixed on the following day. BT confirmed that
it had been caused by a battery failure at one of their exchanges.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:57" start="2004-02-16 00:00" 
end="2004-02-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="42">Fire officers from the UWA visited the site on 16th February 2004
to check the fire extinguishers. All were found to be in working order. </event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:02" start="2004-02-16 00:00" 
end="2004-02-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="46">The new UFAM mobile laboratory arrived at the radar site on 16th February 2004. It will be stored there
in-between campaigns.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 16:57" start="2004-02-17 00:00" 
end="2004-02-18 00:00" author="ZKO" number="43">ZAKO attended a NERC Safety
Responsibility and Risk Management course in Swindon on 17th and 18th February 2004.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:02" start="2004-03-16 00:00" 
end="2004-03-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="47">On 16th March 2004, DAH, SJP and SJW visited the radar site to identify any outstanding Health and
Safety issues and to format a Safety Document.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:03" start="2004-03-20 00:00" 
end="2004-03-22 00:00" author="ZKO" number="48">Over the weekend of 20th March 2004, very high winds coincided with a relay fault in the high voltage
section of the antenna array. Owing to the dangerous conditions, the relay could not replaced until the
morning of 22nd.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:04" start="2004-04-08 00:00" 
end="2004-04-08 00:00" author="ZKO" number="49">On 8th April 2004, a MANWEB (electricity company) employee failed to secure the handbrake on his
van when posting a letter into the mail-box located just within the site gate. The van rolled forward and
demolished a gatepost. MANWEB subsequently completely replaced the post.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:05" start="2004-04-20 00:00" 
end="2004-04-20 00:00" author="ZKO" number="50">On 20th April 2004 the UFAM boundary-layer wind-profiler was taken to Weybourne to participate in
the TORCH campaign.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:05" start="2004-04-29 00:00" 
end="2004-04-29 00:00" author="ZKO" number="51">On 29th April 2004 Jonathan Jones (from the MO) replaced the computer for the GPS water vapour
receiver.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:06" start="2004-05-20 00:00" 
end="2004-05-20 00:00" author="ZKO" number="52">On 20th May 2004, the MST radar was stopped for several hours in order to allow ZAKO carry
out a complete relay check and subsequent repairs.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:07" start="2004-05-25 00:00" 
end="2004-05-25 00:00" author="ZKO" number="53">On 25th May 2004, the MST radar was stopped for several hours in order to allow ZAKO carry
out a complete relay check and subsequent repairs.</event>
<event added="2005-08-01 17:09" start="2004-06-01 13:30" 
end="2004-06-03 10:30" author="ZKO" number="54">The MO's ISDN line developed a fault at 1330 UT on 1st June 2004. It was not rectified by BT until
1030 UT on the 3rd. The fault was found to be 3 miles away from the site. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:07" start="2004-06-21 00:00" 
end="2004-06-21 00:00" author="ZKO" number="55">A new radar observation schedule was introduced on 21st June. Vertical beam observations are now
made every other dwell. These high time resolution observations will be needed for convection, precipitation
and Brunt-Vaisala period determination studies.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:07" start="2004-06-28 00:00" 
end="2004-06-28 00:00" author="ZKO" number="56">A technical problem with the site security system resulted in a Police Rapid Response team being called
to the site twice within a month - the second time on 28th June. The site was temporarily blacklisted by
the Police, until Dyfed alarms retested the system and resolved the problem.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:17" start="2004-07-02 00:00" 
end="2004-07-02 00:00" author="ZKO" number="60">ZAKO carried out work on the antenna array.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:17" start="2004-07-03 00:00" 
end="2004-07-03 00:00" author="ZKO" number="61">ZAKO carried out work on the antenna array</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:09" start="2004-07-04 08:05" 
end="2004-07-05 08:00" author="ZKO" number="57">The locking transmitter went down at 0805 UT on (Sunday) 4th July. This caused the data to be unreliable
until 0800 UT on (Monday) 5th, when ZAKO spotted and fixed the problem.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:17" start="2004-07-10 00:00" 
end="2004-07-10 00:00" author="ZKO" number="62">ZAKO carried out work on the antenna array</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:10" start="2004-07-12 00:00" 
end="2004-07-12 00:00" author="ZKO" number="58">The MST radar was down for about 30 minutes on the afternoon of 12th July. This was to allow MANWEB
to install a new electricity meter for the lidar hut.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:18" start="2004-07-13 00:00" 
end="2004-07-13 00:00" author="ZKO" number="63">ZAKO carried out work on the antenna array</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:11" start="2004-07-19 00:00" 
end="2004-07-19 00:00" author="ZKO" number="59">The tipping bucket raingauge was cleaned on 19th July 
to clear fungus which was preventing the device
from registering rain.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:19" start="2004-08-16 23:30" 
end="2004-08-17 08:35" author="ZKO" number="64">The locking transmitter failed at around 2330 UT on 16th August causing the wind profile data to be
unreliable. ZAKO fixed the problem by 0835 UT on the 17th.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:20" start="2004-08-18 12:35" 
end="2004-08-18 14:05" author="ZKO" number="65">The radar was shut down at around 1235 UT on 18th August because of a fear of a lightning strike. The
thunderstorms, which had persisted for much of the morning, soon cleared and normal operations were
resumed at 1405 UT.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:21" start="2004-08-19 00:00" 
end="2004-08-19 00:00" author="ZKO" number="67">Dyfed Alarms carried out a 6-monthly check on the site alarms, including the panic alarm, on 19th August.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:21" start="2004-08-19 00:00" 
end="2004-08-19 14:00" author="ZKO" number="66">The high voltage unit on one of the transmitters failed on 19th August. The spare transmitted was substituted,
so there was no loss of operations. The unit was fixed and returned to working order by 1400
UT.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:22" start="2004-08-24 00:00" 
end="2004-08-25 00:00" author="ZKO" number="68">A buildings survey was carried out by NERC personnel on 24th August. NERC Health and Safety inspectors
also visited the site on 25th. No serious problems were found.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:23" start="2004-08-25 00:00" 
end="2004-08-25 00:00" author="ZKO" number="69">The tipping bucket raingauge had to be cleaned again on 25th August because of blockage by fungus.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:26" start="2004-09-07 22:00" 
end="2004-09-08 12:00" author="ZKO" number="70">The locking transmitter failed at around 2200 UT on 7th September. This caused corrupt data to be sent
to the Met Office for approximately 8 hours. The problem was spotted first thing on the morning of 8th
by DAH and he was able to block the transmission of data to the Met Office. However, this was during a
week when ZAKO was away on holiday and so it was not until 1200 UT that DaveWareing could switch
the locking transmitter and normal operations were resumed. DAH restarted the transmission of data
to the Met Office later in the afternoon, once he was satisfied that the radar was functioning correctly.
ZAKO repaired the failed transmitter on 12th September, when he had returned from his holiday. DAH
noted that although he had relevant pictures for the procedure of changing the locking transmitter, no
documentation existed.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:27" start="2004-09-14 15:00" 
end="2004-09-14 15:20" author="ZKO" number="71">ZAKO shut down the radar for approximately 20 minutes just after 1500 UT on 14th September. This
was to allow him to check whether a problem with a relay unit had caused the failure of the locking
transmitter on 7th. It wasn't.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:27" start="2004-09-21 00:00" 
end="2004-09-21 00:00" author="ZKO" number="72">On 21st September ZAKO had to take action to remove a virus infection from the Logger PC.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:28" start="2004-10-01 00:00" 
end="2004-10-01 00:00" author="ZKO" number="73">Jonathan Jones, from the Met Office, visited the site on 1st October in order to change the PC on the
GPS water vapour receiver.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:29" start="2004-10-04 07:26" 
end="2004-10-04 07:55" author="ZKO" number="74">An brief power outage caused the radar to stop at around 0726 UT on 4th October. ZAKO restarted the
system immediately on arrival at site at 0755 UT. He also restarted the Met Office's GPS water vapour
receiver PC.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:29" start="2004-10-07 00:00" 
end="2004-10-07 00:00" author="ZKO" number="75">ZAKO cleaned out the tipping bucket raingauge on 7th October.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:30" start="2004-10-14 00:00" 
end="2004-10-14 00:00" author="ZKO" number="76">A NERC audit officer visited the site on 14th October to check on matters relating to access and maintenance.
She found that everything was in order and therefore considered her visit to have been a waste
of time.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:31" start="2004-10-19 08:45" 
end="2004-10-19 15:15" author="ZKO" number="77">At around 0845 UT on 19th October, a jumper failure on MANWEB's high voltage transmission system
caused a power outage in the Capel Dewi area. Power did not return until 1505 UT. The radar was up
and running again by 1515 UT.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:32" start="2004-10-21 16:00" 
end="2004-10-22 07:15" author="ZKO" number="78">The radar was shut down around 1600 UT on 21st October because of fears of a lightning strike. There
had already been power fluctuations which were causing problems for the radar. Thunder continued to
be audible until midnight. The radar was restarted at 0715 UT on 22nd.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:33" start="2004-10-28 00:00" 
end="2004-10-29 00:00" author="ZKO" number="79">ZAKO carried out winter preparations in the field (e.g. securing boxes and cables) on 28th and 29th
October. This did not require the radar to be powered down.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:34" start="2004-11-11 18:30" 
end="2004-11-11 21:30" author="ZKO" number="80">Approximately 10 people from the Ceredigion Amateur Radio Club visited the site from 6:30 - 9:30 pm
on 11th November. They were very interested in the transmitters. A mention of their visit appeared in
the Cambrian News.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:35" start="2004-11-13 13:00" 
end="2004-11-13 13:00" author="ZKO" number="81">A Hercules aircraft flew very low over the radar site, from west to east, at around 1300 UT on 13th
November.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:37" start="2004-11-15 13:45" 
end="2004-11-15 17:15" author="ZKO" number="82">Two engineers from Anritsu visited the radar site on 15th November to demonstrate their hand-held
cable and antenna analyser. The MST radar was shut down from approximately 1345 - 1715 UT in
order to allow them to demonstrate the instrument's capabilities on various parts of the antenna system.
However, the instrument was found to be not working properly.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:38" start="2004-11-17 14:45" 
end="2004-11-18 12:30" author="ZKO" number="83">One of the transmitters went down at around 1445 UT on 17th November after its blower motor seized
up. It was not possible to repair the transmitter, and return it to working order, until around 1230 UT the
following day.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:38" start="2004-11-18 00:00" 
end="2004-11-18 12:00" author="ZKO" number="84">A NERC buildings surveyor visited the site on 18th November in order to inspect the site bungalow and
fence. He finished the survey around 1200 UT the following day.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:39" start="2004-11-18 15:50" 
end="2004-11-18 16:05" author="ZKO" number="85">The radar was down from 1550 - 1605 on 18th November in order to allow ZAKO to carry out an inspection
of the field boxes.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:41" start="2004-11-23 11:00" 
end="2004-11-23 14:00" author="ZKO" number="86">ZAKO received a working cable and antenna analyser from Anritsu on 22nd November. The radar was
down from 1100 - 1400 UT on the 23rd in order to allow him to test 30 of the 100 quads with the unit.
</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2004-11-24 00:00" 
end="2004-11-30 00:00" author="ZKO" number="87">
Dave Wareing and EGN tried out the antenna analyser from Anritsu on the UFAM equipment on 24th. It was found to
be useful in both cases. The Logger PC was used to download the field test data from the instrument.
The use of the Logger PC in this way appears to have disrupted the normal collection of data from the
Campbell Scientific instruments. This was not noticed, and rectified, until 30th November. Although
this led to the loss of several day's worth of surface wind data, the surface met data appear to be complete.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:46" start="2004-11-30 12:45" 
end="2004-11-30 15:45" author="ZKO" number="88">Students from the UWA Institute of Geography and Earth Sciences visited the site on 30th November in
order to carry out their surveying practical. This required the radar to be shut down from approximately
1245 - 1545 UT.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2004-12-15 00:00" 
end="2004-12-15 00:00" author="ZKO" number="89">
NERC carried out an electrical survey of the site bungalow on 15th
December 2004. Recommendations for changes included replacing the
existing storage heaters with gas or oil on-demand units, and possibly
even recycling heat from the transmitters. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2004-12-17 00:00" 
end="2004-12-17 00:00" author="ZKO" number="90">
The MO's GPS water
vapour receiver PC was rebooted on 17th December.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2004-12-24 07:00" 
end="2004-12-24 07:00" author="ZKO" number="92">
A fault caused the site alarm to go off at 07 UT on 24th
December. Dyfed alarms changed a sensor in the lounge area.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2004-12-29 00:00" 
end="2004-12-29 00:00" author="ZKO" number="91">
The MO's GPS water
vapour receiver PC was rebooted on 29th
December.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-01-03 20:00" 
end="2005-01-04 09:00" author="ZKO" number="93">
A non-locking transmitter went down during the night of 3rd/4th
January 2005. This was fixed by 09 UT on 4th January. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-01-06 00:00" 
end="2005-01-11 00:00" author="ZKO" number="94">
The timber next
to the smaller of the two site sheds was collected for disposal on 6th
and 11th January. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-01-12 00:00" 
end="2005-01-12 00:00" author="ZKO" number="95">
The new Anritsu cable testing unit arrived at the
site on 12th January.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-01-14 12:00" 
end="2005-01-15 19:30" author="ZKO" number="96">
TX1, the locking transmitter, failed at around
1200 UT on Friday 14th January. The problem was not spotted until the
following evening (Saturday 15th). All transmitters were locked and
working again by 1930 UT on 15th.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-01-22 08:00" 
end="2005-01-23 10:00" author="ZKO" number="97">
A problem with the radar control PC
caused observations to stop at around 08 UT on 22nd January (a
Saturday). The problem was spotted by DAH first thing on the following
Monday morning and normal operations resumed at around 10 UT. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-01-26 00:00" 
end="2005-01-26 00:00" author="ZKO" number="98">
Some
work was carried out in the field on 26th January. This did not
require the radar to be shut down. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-01-27 07:30" 
end="2005-01-27 09:45" author="ZKO" number="99">
A control cable to relay unit 21
developed a short circuit at around 0730 UT on 27th January. This
caused the radar to malfunction until the cable was by-passed at
around 0945 UT. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-02-07 00:00" 
end="2005-02-15 00:00" author="ZKO" number="100">
TX2 was repaired on 15th February. It had been out of action since 7th
February, when Dave Wareing received a burn from it whilst ZAKO was on
leave. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-02-15 00:00" 
end="2005-02-15 00:00" author="ZKO" number="101">
15th February. The PC controlling the MO's GPS water vapour receiver also required
reboot. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-02-16 00:00" 
end="2005-02-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="102">
DAH and ZAKO attempted to remove worm infections from the
Logger PC on 16th February. It appears that these infections were
preventing the Sophos anti-virus software from updating. However, the
infections proved hard to remove and so further action was delayed
until the PC could be returned to RAL for a more thorough
investigation. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-02-22 00:00" 
end="2005-02-22 00:00" author="ZKO" number="103">
Katie Abbott, from NERC, visited the site on 22nd
February in order to carry out a site survey.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-02-23 00:00" 
end="2005-02-24 00:00" author="ZKO" number="104">
Field work was carried
out on 23rd and 24th February. This did not require the radar to be
powered down. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-02-28 00:00" 
end="2005-02-28 00:00" author="ZKO" number="105">
UofWA fire officer visited the site on 28th February in
order to carry out checks on the fire extinguishers. No problems were
found. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-01 11:45" 
end="2005-03-01 12:45" author="ZKO" number="106">
One of the non-locking transmitters was out of action between 11:45
and 12:45 UT on 1st March to allow work be carried out on it. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-02 00:00" 
end="2005-03-03 00:00" author="ZKO" number="107">
Work on
the relays was carried out on 2nd and 3rd March. This did not require
any down time. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-04 08:50" 
end="2005-03-04 11:45" author="ZKO" number="108">
The extractor fan seized on one of the transmitters at
08:50 UT on 4th March. It was switched off between 10:45 and 11:45 UT
to allow a replacement be fitted. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-09 12:45" 
end="2005-03-09 18:15" author="ZKO" number="109">
The MST radar was down 12:45 - 18:15
UT on 9th March to allow work to
be carried out on the field relays. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-10 13:00" 
end="2005-03-10 15:45" author="ZKO" number="110">
The MST radar was down 13:00 - 15:45 UT on 10th March to allow work to
be carried out on the field relays. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-11 00:00" 
end="2005-03-11 00:00" author="ZKO" number="111">
The surface met data logging unit,
tipping bucket rain gauge and (faulty) humidity sensor were sent back
to Campbell Scientific for recalibration and repairs on 11th
March. The fact that the pressure sensor could not be found gave the
first indication that it may have been stolen. At first it was thought
that it had simply developed a fault. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-14 15:30" 
end="2005-03-14 15:30" author="ZKO" number="112">
The MST radar was down 11:30 -
15:30 on 14th March to allow the replacement of some relays. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-16 00:00" 
end="2005-03-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="113">
The RAL
cloud radar arrived at the MST site, direct from its recent field
campaign in Mauritius, on 16th March. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-17 11:30" 
end="2005-03-17 15:30" author="ZKO" number="114">
The MST radar was down for two
brief periods, around 11:30 UT and around 15:30 UT, on 17th March to
allow work to be carried out on the relays. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-18 09:00" 
end="2005-03-18 16:00" author="ZKO" number="115">
There were a number of
mains fluctuations during 18th March which caused problems for the
MST radar: at around 09 UT, between 12:30 and
14:30 UT, and at around 15:20 UT. The radar was shut down again, just
after 16 UT, to allow repairs be carried out in the field. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-31 00:00" 
end="2005-03-31 00:00" author="ZKO" number="117">
31st March - The surface met data logger, and sensors,
arrived back from Campbell Scientific. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-03-31 08:30" 
end="2005-03-31 09:15" author="ZKO" number="116">
One of the
MST radar transmitters went down at around 08:30 UT on 31st March, but
was repaired by 09:15 UT. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-05 00:00" 
end="2005-04-05 00:00" author="ZKO" number="118">
The data logger and met sensors (apart from the replacement pressure
sensor) were reinstalled on 5th April. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-06 00:00" 
end="2005-04-07 00:00" author="ZKO" number="119">
A new MST radar observation
format was introduced on 6th April to allow a single vertical beam
mesospheric observation to be made during each ST-mode cycle. At first
an 8 mus pulse, with no pulse coding, was used. However, for some
reason this caused the radar to operate in an unstable manner and so 2
mus coding was introduced on 7th. This solved the problem. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-13 00:00" 
end="2005-04-13 00:00" author="ZKO" number="120">
DAH
installed "Nero", the new WindowsXP data logging PC, on 13th
April. The old PC was taken back to RAL for disinfection.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-14 00:00" 
end="2005-04-14 00:00" author="ZKO" number="121">
The cut
wires from the stolen original pressure sensor were discovered whilst
DAH and ZAKO were replacing the new pressure sensor in the data
logging box on 14th April. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-14 00:00" 
end="2005-04-14 00:00" author="ZKO" number="122">
Peter Huggard and Tim Nightingale, from
RAL, arrived on site on the afternoon of 14th April to set up the
cloud radar. The instrument was in operation by the end of the
day. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-16 11:00" 
end="2005-04-16 12:45" author="ZKO" number="123">
The blower motor on one of the MST radar transmitters had
disintegrated at some time on 16th April (a Saturday). This was
discovered at 11:00 UT on 16th and the blower motor was replaced
by 12:45 UT. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-18 14:30" 
end="2005-04-18 14:30" author="ZKO" number="124">
The tipping bucket raingauge was cleaned out at 14:30 UT
on 18th April. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-22 00:00" 
end="2005-05-04 08:00" author="ZKO" number="126">
On 4th May ZAKO returned from holiday and by 08 UT the two MST radar
transmitters which had been down since the 22nd April power
disruptions were restarted. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-04-22 14:00" 
end="2005-04-25 08:00" author="ZKO" number="125">
Mains interruptions caused the MST radar to stop
working at around 14:00 UT on Friday 22nd April, whilst ZAKO was away
on holiday. The problem was not spotted until first thing on Monday
25th April by DAH. Since the radar had come back up cleanly, DAH was
able to restart data acquisition remotely at just after 08 UT. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-05-05 00:00" 
end="2005-05-10 00:00" author="ZKO" number="127">
On 5th May ZAKO discovered that the new
pressure sensor had been stolen. This was reported to the Police
who came out immediately. Dave Wareing discovered a hole in the
security fence (on the stretch running parallel to the road) on 9th
May. The Police re-visited the site on 10th May.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-05-12 00:00" 
end="2005-05-12 00:00" author="ZKO" number="128">
The grass was cut on
12th May. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-05-20 12:00" 
end="2005-05-20 19:00" author="ZKO" number="129">
A mains disruption at around 12 UT on 20th May caused an
exceptional amount of damage. Two of the transmitters were out of
action and a chip blew on the antenna control board.  The system was
restored to working order and normal operations resumed at 19
UT. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-05-22 00:00" 
end="2005-05-22 08:00" author="ZKO" number="130">
Failure of the UPS unit which powered the radar acquisition
systems at around 00 UT on Sunday 22nd May caused the radar to be out
of action until just after 08 UT on the following morning. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-01 00:00" 
end="2005-06-01 00:00" author="ZKO" number="131">
One of the MST radar transmitters (a non-locking one) went down
overnight on 1st June and was restarted in the morning. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-01 00:00" 
end="2005-06-06 00:00" author="ZKO" number="132">
The UFAM
boundary-layer wind-profiler was taken from the MST site on 1st June
to be used in the CSIP campaign. The mobile lidar was taken on 6th
June. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-08 12:30" 
end="2005-06-08 16:45" author="ZKO" number="133">
The cloud radar was switched off at around 12:30 UT on 8th June
because the temperature of the antenna unit rose too high. It was
switched back on around 16:45 UT. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-10 00:00" 
end="2005-06-14 00:00" author="ZKO" number="134">
ZAKO carried out work in the field on
10th and 14th June. There was no need to power down the MST radar. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-16 00:00" 
end="2005-06-16 00:00" author="ZKO" number="135">
PC
Pat Jalloal, a Community Safety Officer from Dyfed-Powys Police,
visited the site on 16th June. He gave recommendations on how to
improve site security.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-17 00:00" 
end="2005-06-17 00:00" author="ZKO" number="136">
The cloud radar was stopped on 17th June and
moved from where it had been in operation (immediately to the north of the
bungalow). This was to allow the ground to be excavated for the new
instrument platform. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-18 00:00" 
end="2005-06-18 00:00" author="ZKO" number="137">
A digger was on site on Saturday 18th. It also
excavated the ground where one of the old sheds had been. This area
will have a car port built on it. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-19 19:00" 
end="2005-06-20 08:00" author="ZKO" number="138">
A failure of a UPS unit at around 19
UT on Sunday 19th June caused MST radar data to stop being
acquired. The problem was fixed at around 08 UT the following
morning. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-23 00:00" 
end="2005-06-23 00:00" author="ZKO" number="139">
ZAKO carried out work on the MST antennas on 23rd June. This did not
require the radar to be powered down.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-06-28 17:15" 
end="2005-06-29 07:30" author="ZKO" number="140">
 The MST radar was shut down at
around 17:15 UT on 28th June because of thunderstorms in the area. The
thunderstorms caused extensive damage to equipment at the UofWA. The
radar was switched back on at 07:30 UT the following morning.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-07-01 00:00" 
end="2005-07-01 00:00" author="ZKO" number="141">
The concrete for the new instrument platform was poured and levelled on
1st July. The concreting for the car port will be done at a later
date. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-07-04 15:45" 
end="2005-07-04 15:45" author="ZKO" number="142">
The cloud radar was placed on the new instrument platform and
restarted around 15:45 UT on 4th July. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-07-05 00:00" 
end="2005-07-05 00:00" author="ZKO" number="143">
The grass was cut on 5th
July. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-07-08 09:00" 
end="2005-07-08 10:15" author="ZKO" number="144">
The MST radar was stopped between 09:00 and 10:15 UT on 8th July
to allow ZAKO to carry out work on the relays.</event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-07-09 00:00" 
end="2005-07-09 00:00" author="ZKO" number="145">
Weed spraying was
carried out on 9th July. </event>
<event added="2005-08-02 13:45" start="2005-07-15 00:00" 
end="2005-07-15 00:00" author="ZKO" number="146">
The cloud radar was shut down at 11 UT
because the temperature of the antenna unit was rising too high. It
was switched back on on 15th July. </event>
</eventlog>
